#### Nibil M S

Email: me@nibil.in / msnibil@gmail.com

(m): +91-9495 41 2790

skype: nibilms

### **Summary**

I'm a Techno-Functional professional who started my career as the first employee of a startup after completion of my engineering course in Computer Science and Engineering. I started off as a development engineer, later on transitioning myself to a managerial role in the second tier leadership of the company while continuing my role as a Product Engineer in the company. In my 5-year stint with the startup, the company grew from 5 to 72 people. I have had the opportunity to experience the initial hiccups, the effective bootstrapping, external investment and the growth of the company from multiple roles and perspectives.

I then moved on to a company which was then bootstrapping and is now heading the developing team. I am deeply involved in every development activity that is happening in the company. Also I am having client interactions around the globe. I am also utilizing my free time to give advices for another team which I have built and is working on a prestigious product named Talenter.

# **Work Experience**

# **Lead Engineer (December 2016 to Present)**

Rawdata Technologies, Kerala ( <u>www.rawdatatech.com</u>)

- Reporting directly to the CEO, responsible in the handling services around the globe.
- Interact with clients to understand client's requirement, check feasibility & provide best suitable estimation accordingly.
- Deeply involved in recruiting developers into the team.
- Do code reviews and appraisals of developers.

# **Product Lead - Consultant Role (October 2016 to Present)**

Peoplytics, Kerala

- Reporting directly to the Managing Director , responsible in the development of the product Talenter.
- Define the features and software architecture of Talenter
- Recruit, onboard and train people and build a strong team to work on Talenter.

#### VP of Data Research (March 2015 to August 2016)

Profoundis Labs Private Ltd, Kerala

- Profoundis developed their flagship product (<a href="https://vibeapp.co">https://vibeapp.co</a>) backed by a Human + Technology Hybrid engine which has been acquired by FullContact.
- As there was a need to grow Data Research as a function in the company, I gradually transitioned into a business role with client interactions.
- Directly reporting to Co-founder & Chief of Data Research, I led the operations side of data research function with the whole Data Research Team functionally reporting to me.
- Was also involved deeply in the recruitment, onboarding, training, performance appraisals as the team grew from 10 to 72.
- Part of the team that developed and maintained the internal Django webapp that augmented the Data Research process.
- Python language scripting.

#### Senior Product Engineer (July 2012 to February 2015)

Profoundis Labs Private Ltd, Kerala (<a href="www.profoundis.com">www.profoundis.com</a>)

- Joined Profoundis as the first employee after the first month of the company's inception.
- Reporting directly to the CTO of the company; responsible for the services side of Profoundis which was then bootstrapping.
- Worked with clients from Turkey, Middle East and the US including the likes of Vodafone which cumulatively earned over 100,000\$ for the company.
- Mostly worked with Python, Django, HTML and Javascript during this tenure.

## Django Developer ( August 2011 to June 2012)

As a prodigy of Mr. Kenneth Gonsalves (Chairman, Indian Python Software Society, 2010 2011)

- Worked on multiple projects including development and maintenance of Websites and Web applications in Python/Django.
- Clients included FIDA Kids (an NGO based out of Africa and India), Bamboo Banks (Ooty based hotel) and Ooty Golf Course.

#### Education

- Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering 2007-2011
  Vinayaka Missions University, Salem 74.20%
- Higher Secondary Examination, March 2007
  Govt Higher Secondary School, Kumaranellur 84%
- Technical High School Leaving Certificate, March 2005
  Technical Higher Secondary School, Vattamkulam 81.80%

# **Technical Skills**

- Programming Languages and Frameworks:
  - Python, Django
- Databases
  - PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite
- Operating Systems
  - GNU/Linux: both Redhat & Debian, Mac OSX, All Microsoft Windows Environments.

#### **Management Skills**

- Business sense with technology background.
- Leadership, Interpersonal and team skills
- Initiating, leading and optimizing day to day operations of a team at scale.
- Recruiting and building a team

# **Personal Information**

Name : Nibil M S Sex : Male

Address : Needam, Trithala P.O, Palakkad-679534, Kerala, IN

Date of Birth : 06-10-1989 Marital Status : Married

Passport : Indian (#K3080682) Languages Known : English, Malayalam, Tamil

# **Declaration**

I hereby declare that all information given by me is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Nibil M S